Gregg Smith Papers
Gregg Smith Papers
- Compositions
  - Unpublished choral manuscripts
    - Somewhere over the rainbow, score and sketch, marked, computer printout copies (Box 10)
    - Sonata for harp, full score, copied and bound (Box 10)
    - Songs of the sea, score and sketches, mix of handwritten and handwritten copies (Oversize 38)
    - Space age murmurs, photocopied portions with handwritten additions (Oversize 38)
    - Sudden as sweet, 12/24/1995; "written for St. Peter's in thanks and love for 25 years of association"; computer printout (Box 10)
    - Suite for harp, handwritten (Oversize 38)
    - Swan Sequence, full score, computer printout (Box 10)
    - Take my mother home, handwritten copy (Box 10)
    - Theme and variations, handwritten copy (Box 10)
    - This land, score, handwritten and incomplete computer printout; scores by others which Smith studied while arranging his version (Oversize 38)
    - Thou didst delight mine eyes, handwritten copies (Box 10)
    - Three chorales, score and parts, mix of handwritten and copies (Oversize 38)
    - Toccata del rio, handwritten copies (Box 10)
    - Tom's rock, computer printout (Box 10)
    - Traveller, score, computer printout; text, handwritten sketches, and computerized revisions of early sketch (Oversize 38)
    - Trio on an American Folk Song, full score, vellums and copies; 2 folders (Oversize 38)
    - Trio on an American Folk Song, score, copied and bound (Box 10)
    - Trio sonata, handwritten copies (Box 10)
    - Two divine poems, words by John Donne; score, copied and bound (Box 10)
    - Vasatka hymn, computer printout (Box 10)
    - Waltzing Matilda, handwritten copy (Box 10)
    - West Virginia, full scores, computer printouts with edits; text of poem by Louis O'Neill (Box 10)
    - When the bloom is on the sage, handwritten copy (Box 10)
    - When I hear music, "an anniversary song for Gordon"; vellums and vellum copy (Oversize 38)
    - Who is the man, handwritten copies (Box 10)
    - Wilderness, full score, handwritten; 1 pg copied (Oversize 38)
    - Wilt thou not ope thy heart to know, handwritten draft, copy of later version (Oversize 38)
    - Windows in time, computer printout (Box 10)
    - Wondrous love, handwritten copy (Box 10)
    - Yemey Hachanuka, handwritten with typed words, copy (Box 10)
    - Yvonne's song, draft handwritten copy (Box 10)
    - Untitled, incomplete choral work related to Jacob (Oversize 38)
- Correspondence
  - American Masters program, NEA, 2007 (Box 10)
  - Biggs, E. Power, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
  - CBS Records, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Europe, Ithaca Choir, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Foss, Lukas (photocopy), 1997; re Earth Requiem (Box 10)
  - Heinsheimer, H.W., 1963-1964; re Israeli folksong Adama (Box 10)
  - Hill, Paul (Paul Hill Chorale), 1990 (Box 10)
  - Jeffers, Ron (Earthsongs), 2004; re Jamaican Songs corrections and questions (Box 10)
  - Liebig, Phoebe, 2017 (Box 10)
  - McClure, John (Columbia Records), 1966-1967 (Box 10)
  - Miles, Mrs. Edward J., 1967 (Box 10)
  - St. Peter's Church, 2005 (Box 10)
  - Schirmer, 1991, 2001; re Epigrams, Jerusalem (Box 10)
  - Shapiro, Mark, 2007-2008; re Mass in Space; includes copy of score with markings (Box 10)
  - Siskind, Paul A. (Box 11)
  - Soler recordings, Zurich, 1967; recording for CBS Records; includes John McClure, Frederick Marvin, others (Box 11)
  - "Songs from a liberal heart", 2017; includes 1 pg computer printout, list of files on Finale, etc. (Box 11)
  - Southern Illinois Children's Choir, 1993-1994; re commission for Sandburg pieces (Box 11)
  - Stevens, Denis, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Tagg, Barbara (Adirondack Children's Chorus) (Box 11)
  - Texas Boys Choir, 1967; George Bragg, Jack White (Box 11)
  - Thorne, Francis (photocopy), 1997; re Earth Requiem (Box 11)
  - Weitzenkamp, Carol, re Carol's Canon (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 2001-2002; 2005,; 2017,; undated; includes note from Smith regarding Regina Coeli and Stabat Mater (A Mary Trilogy?) (Box 11)
- Memorabilia
  - Adirondack Children's Chorus, 1995; pictures and poems (Box 11)
    See also Compositions: Unpublished choral manuscripts: Adirondack Children's Songs for related work.
  - Binder stamped with Smith's name, originally contained score for Magnificat I (Box 4)
  - Calendars and itineraries, 1969; 1971,; 1973-1975,; 1977; 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Calendars and itineraries, 1979-1988; 13 folders (Box 12)
  - Clippings, 1967; 1983,; 1996-1997,; 2001,; includes reviews of Earth Requiem, The Storyteller (Box 12)
  - Epigrams of Gomer Rees, 2018; published booklet (Box 12)
  - Gregg Smith 50th birthday party, Saranac Lake, 1981 (Box 12)
  - List of canons, photocopy, 2pp. (Box 12)
  - List of songs titles with names of singers[?], in pencil on cardboard (Oversize 40)
  - Music for an Urban Church, smith_gre_005; commercial recording of several pieces by Smith, including Jazz Mass for St. Peter's, Dedication Theme and Variations on 'Our Father'; Lord you give the great commission; Seven stanzas at Easter; Songs from a liberal heart; and Missa brevis (Mass for St. Peter's); CD; running time 72:10 (Box 18)
  - "Pretty Good Company" opening, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Programs
    - Double Sonata, 1983; includes typed draft of program notes (Box 13)
    - Earth Requiem, 1997; premier, National Cathedral, Washington DC with flier advertising it; New York premier in Long Island (Box 13)
    - Magnificat I, 1989, undated; Los Angeles and New York performances, plus Jude Otten's rehearsal notes and schedule for Philadelphia performance (Box 13)
    - The Storyteller, 1996-1998 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1984-1985; 1988,; 1992-1993,; 1995,; 2005,; 2012,; 2016,; 2018,; undated (Box 13)
  - Seating chart for Penfield Symphony, undated (Box 13)
  - Study guide for Cathedral Choir concert attendees, 1997; intended to prepare concert goers for concerts that season; includes profile of Smith and "Composer's Notes" on Earth Requiem (Box 13)
  - Tour miscellany, mostly receipts and other expense documentation
    - Far east, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Far east, 1982 (Box 13)
    - US, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Scandinavia, 1983 (Box 13)
    - US, 1983 (Box 13)
    - Far east, 1984 (Box 13)
    - US, 1984 (Box 13)
    - US, 1985 (Box 14)
    - US, 1986 (Box 14)
    - US, 1987 (Box 14)
    - US, 1988 (Box 14)
    - US, 1989; 2 folders (Box 14)
- Published octavos
  The number in parentheses after a title indicates the number of copies.
  - Aesop's Fables, movements 1-10 (Box 15)
  - A (Box 15)
    Ahay tuburan (2)
    Alleluia: Vom himmel hoch (3)
    America the beautiful (3, plus proof sheets and duplication masters)
    Ave Maria (2)
  - Ba-Be (Box 15)
    Babel (2)
    The best things are close (2 photocopies + 2 pages)
  - Bi-Bl (Box 15)
    Bible songs for young voices (2)
    Blow the candles out (2)
    The Blue-tail fly (2)
  - A Child's garden of verses (Box 15)
    Foreign lands (2)
    Singing (2)
    Whole duty of children (2)
  - Christmas (Box 15)
    Christmas suite, photocopies (1 copy each of 2 songs)
    Christmas time book I (2)
    Christmas time book II (2)
  - Co-Cu (Box 15)
    Concert rounds on old sayings (2, plus 2 faint photocopies of lists of sayings)
    Concert madrigals (2)
    The Cuckoo (2)
  - Doo-wop madrigals, some have markings (Box 15)
    Billings in blue (2)
    Cool April (2)
    Hey, babe (2)
    He's awesome (2)
    Multiple echoes (2)
    My heart is longing for your love (2)
    Oh! That love and beauty (2)
    The Revecy Band (2)
  - D (Box 15)
    Deck the halls (2)
    Drunken sailor (2)
  - Emily's Autumn (2 copies prepped for publication) (Box 15)
  - E (Box 16)
    Eleven palindromes (2)
    Epigrams (2)
  - F-G (Box 16)
    Fear not, good shepherds (from Bible songs for young voices)
    Four Concord chorales: Music (2), Beauty (2), Nature (2), and Spirit (2)
    Glädjens Blomster (Fairest flowers)
  - H (Box 16)
    Holiday harmonies, complete - full score (2)
    Holiday harmonies, complete - SA parts (2)
    Holiday harmonies I: All hail to the days/In praise of Christmas (2)
    Holiday harmonies II: Green grows the holly (2)
    Holiday harmonies III: Merry Christmas/On Christmas Eve (2)
    High Barbary (2)
    The Hutchinsons: The horticultural wife (1)
  - I remember (2) (Box 16)
  - J (Box 16)
    Jamaican songs I: Sing (2)
    Jamaican songs II: The Road (2)
    Jamaican songs III: Let us build (2)
    Jamaican songs IV: On this night (2)
    Jerusalem (2, also photocopies labeled "first proofs")
  - L (Box 16)
    Landscapes (2)
    Latin madrigals (2)
    Das Lieben bringt gross freud (2)
    Listen to the mockingbird (2)
    A Long long time ago (N'ia gaire que auvit) (2)
    The Lord bless thee and keep thee (2)
    The Lord is my shepherd (from Bible Songs for Young Voices) (1)
  - A Mary trilogy (Box 16)
    Complete piano reduction (2)
    I. Ave Maria (2)
    II. Regina coeli (2)
    III. Salve regina (2)
    Proofs for publication, with publisher's questions/notes
  - Mass in Space, piano-vocal (2) (Box 16)
  - Missa pro Roger Wagner (2) (Box 16)
  - N (Box 16)
    Now I walk in beauty, copy of unison melody laid in (2)
    Now it is Yule again (2)
  - O (Box 17)
    O Jeanie there's naething to fear ye (2)
    O Tannenbaum (1)
    O how beautiful (2)
    On the beach at night (1)
  - P (Box 17)
    Papa Bach (2)
    Pastores a belen (2; 1 is director's copy with markup)
    Patapan (2)
    Plaudite (2)
  - R (Box 17)
    The Railroad corral (2)
    Riqui, Riqui, Riqurran (2)
  - S-Sil (Box 17)
    S'vivon / Dreydl song (2)
    Set me as a seal (2)
    Seven Stanzas at Easter (2, copies of text laid in)
    Shakespeare madrigals (1)
    Shenandoah (2, 1 with markings)
    The Silver swan (2)
  - Sim-Som (Box 17)
    A Simple mass (2)
    Sing of spring (2)
    Some folks (2 photocopies of marked-up published edition)
  - Song (Box 17)
    A Song from Mr. Wilde (photocopy, with markings)
    Songs of innocence, from Beware the soldier (2)
    Songs from a liberal heart (2, 1 with markups/corrections)
  - Sou-Su (Box 17)
    Sound canticle on Bay Psalm 23 (2 photocopies for publication, with notes)
    Stehn zwei stern (2)
    Suogon (2)
  - T (Box 17)
    Three Justin Morgan choruses: Despair, Amanda, Montgomery (2, with markings)
    The Twelve days of Christmas (2, 1 marked and missing front cover)
    Two Whitman songs (3, 1 is incomplete)
  - W (Box 17)
    Welcome home (2)
    Wexford carol (2)